CURRICULUM VITAE

Manohar Jadhav

Sr. Software Engineer / Data Analyst

Email: jadhav.manohar84@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/manohar-jadhav-9b716115b/

Mobile: +919901468300

Objective:

Creative Senior Software Engineer / Data Analyst offering 14+ years of experience. Enthusiastic about developing forward-thinking solutions to tomorrow's productivity problems. I am a highly motivated and ambitious individual, able to give timely and accurate advice, guidance and support to the team members. More documentation of experience, references and skills are available upon requirement.

Professional Experience:

- Solid understanding of Data Analytics and Strong working knowledge of development techniques and methodologies
- 6+ years of experience in Business Intelligent Tools like Power BI
- Proven track record in designing, modeling and analyses of data for Business Intelligent (BI)
 applications
- Good hands on Azure Data Factory (ADF)
- Hands on Snowflake Database, Azure Databricks (Spark SQL, Py spark), Google BigQuery's with ETL (Extract, Transform and Load)
- Over 5 years of experience in Database Architecture, Database Creation, Database
 Management and Data Integration
- 3+ years of experience in Application Architecture and Development
- Exceptional communication and presentation skills with an established track record of successful client interactions, strong analytical thinking, multi-tasking and problem solving skills
- Self-supervised professional, with strong team management skills and ability to think outside
 of the box, Result oriented with excellent time management and organization skills.

Work Experience Summary:

- Currently working as Sr. Software Engineer / Data Analyst in iNetFrame Technologies Pvt. Ltd.
 from June 2020
- Worked as Sr. Software Engineer (Team Lead) in IDS Technologies India Pvt. Ltd. from April 2017 to May 2020
- Worked as Software Engineer in Creintors Teknosol Pvt. Ltd. from Feb 2009 to April 2017

Education Profile:

Completed Diploma in Computer Science from Vasantrao Potdar Polytechnic, Belgaum

affiliated to Board of Technical Education, Bangalore

Technical Skills:

Analytics and Business Intelligence : Power BI, Tableau, Google Analytics

Cloud Based ETL Tools : Azure Data Factory, Snowflake

Database : MSSQL, MySQL
Cloud Technologies : Microsoft Azure
DevOps : Azure DevOps

Projects Description:

Project #5

Title: HQM (Hospital Quality Management)
Client: BCBSRI, Rhode Island, United States

Role: Project Lead, Data Analyst and Power BI Developer

Team Size: 12+

Duration: January 2022 - Till Date

Tools Used: Microsoft Azure: Cloud Computing Services (Azure Data Factory, Azure Active Directory

B2B, ExpressJS, Angular 12, MSSQL, Azure Storage), JSON Rules Engine, Power BI

Description: HQM is an application to automate the time-consuming manual process of measuring the quality of Hospitals and payment calculation for achieving the target goals. The manual payout calculation is a complex process and to resolve this hindrance, HQM is built to ease the process of critical decisions and calculations. Since there are approximately 27 types of measures for each hospital and getting the targets of each hospital manually is a cumbersome process HQM solves this issue in an effective way with Business Intelligence Reports.

Project #4

Title: Reports Migration – Tableau to Power BI

Client: BCBSRI, Rhode Island, United States

Role: Team Lead and Data Analyst

Team Size: 4+

Duration: March 2021 – December 2021

Tools Used: Power BI, Azure Databricks, Google Bigquery

Description: Migration of all Dashboards developed in Tableau to Power BI with additional functionalities

and design changes.

Project #3

Title: Medicare Advantage Lead Management

Client: BCBSRI, Rhode Island, United States
Role: Data Analyst and Power BI Developer

Team Size: 6+

Duration: June 2020 – March 2021

Tools Used: Power BI, MSSQL, Angular 2+, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap

Description: Medicare LeadGen is a product aimed to solve the lead generation problem for the Medicare population. In simple terms, Medicare LeadGen builds a good quality sales lead for insurance companies to target the Medicare population. This is a "Specialized Salesforce application for healthcare targeted for Medicare".

Project #2

Title: IDS Biz – Business Process Automation for Readymix Industry

Client: National Concrete Company, Bahrain
Role: .Net Developer and Power BI Developer

Team Size: 10+

Duration: April 2017 – May 2020 Tools Used: **Power BI, Visual Studio**

Description: An ERP application for Readymix industry to Automate Business Processes with Automatic

Planning and Scheduling feature.

Project #1

Title: Insert & Tools Management System

Client: In-house (Creintors Teknosol Pvt. Ltd.)

Role: Java Developer

Team Size: 8+

Duration: January 2015 – February 2017

Tools Used: Eclipse

Description: Fully Automatic Insert & Tool Dispensing System with data acquisition. Advanced with Inventory Management Software with Reporting System. And secured with RFID, Biometric Thumb and Password Protected.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Completed hands-on configuration and custom development of Business Intelligence reports in Power BI and Tableau, using advanced queries to achieve reporting requirements, within performance constraints.
- Responsible for Data Extraction from various Data sources, Data Manipulation, Data management, Data Cleansing (De-Duplication) etc.
- Hands on experience in Power BI Desktop on various charts like Heat Map, Tree Map, Bar Chart,
 Line Chart, Scatter Plot, Bubble Chart, Pie Chart, Dual Axis Charts and Geographical charts like
 Filled Map and Symbol Maps which helps the management to take quick decisions and can access
 quick filters to drill down the information and can understand in effective and concise manner.
- Hands on experience in working with Power BI Desktop Building quick views, Sorting, Grouping,
 Hierarchy, Table Calculations, Functions, Advanced Filtering, Sets, Page Trials, Action Filters,
 Parameters, SQL Joins, Data Blending, Cross Tab, Reports Formatting, Data Extracts, Incremental
 Refresh, packaged workbooks, Dashboards and publish on server etc.
- Developed Power BI workbooks to perform year over year, quarter over quarter, YTD, QTD and MTD type of analysis.
- Created Drill-down and Sub-Report using various data sources. Monitored the performance of the reports.
- Generated Dashboards with Quick filters, Parameters and sets to handle views more efficiently.
- Generated context filters and data source filters while handling huge volume of data.
- Responsible to design Solution Architecture and development logics.
- Responsible for understanding and gathering business requirements from various stakeholders, business leaders and translate the requirements into Reporting, Interactive visualization, and Dashboards.
- Responsible to build pipelines using Azure Data Factory.
- Prepare and present design and architectural concepts and recommendations to project team.
- Assigning Tasks to Team Members and keeping track of all development tasks.
- Ensuring that the team is motivated, monitored and measured in line with the company targets and performance standards.
- Responsible for making sure that any gaps in performance or quality are quickly identified and addressed.
- Producing Solution Document, Design Document, Technical Reports documentation on project and team performance for senior managers and management.